Research data should be free, shareable, and re-usable.
Only when open, it will reach its true potential.
Fostering collaboration, open data accelerates research,
even years after its production, by allowing easy preliminary and meta-analyses,
it can put research on the right track.
Open data provides a bulletproof defense
against accusations of misconduct or bad scientific practices.
Open data increases research visibility and citations,
and when well organised, open data can also speed up the research process.
Trustworthy results are efficiently and safely delivered,
and the research gets more chance to be published and funded.
Governments, funding agencies, universities, and publishers
have recognised the importance of opening up research data.
and now, they often REQUEST it, and rightfully so.
But producing open data does not come without difficulties,
it can require a modification of the research workflow,
a process that does not come without pain and effort.
But once data management has been implemented, opening data is effortless.
By default, the data are Findable, Accessible, Interoperable and Re-usable,
and can be made open by the press of a button.
In the end, good research always wins!
When the times comes, it is a job for researchers.
For their careers and for society, they have to unleash their data:
they must make it open and FAIR,
And their open FAIR data will fly away and save the day.
If you want to master data management and produce open data, look for help at a Research Data Management Helpdesk or online!
Translation: XXX
In the next episode, we will see how Research Data Management can help you retrieve your data, so stay tuned!