Why research data management 2/4:
Retrieving Data
Researchers do love their data
And if their data are lost, the dance stops.
While researchers can avoid
the crash of a complete data loss by creating backups,
proper data management goes
beyond just preventing a crash.
Today, data are accumulating faster and faster
While packaging their data for future analysis, reuse, and sharing,
researchers often lack a proper system.
This strategy may work for a time
but when the amount and complexity of datasets increases,
researchers can put themselves in real danger!
Because you do not want to waste days sorting out your data,
you shall master data safety, organization, naming and computer readability.
Then, the research process happens smoothly and efficiently.
If you want to master data management and increase your efficiency, look for help at a Research Data Management Helpdesk or online.
Translation: XXX
In the next episode, we will see how research data management can help you with your data analysis, so stay tuned!