Why research data management 1/4:
Analysing data
Research is a long process that often relies on data.
Data are collected, documented, processed,
preserved, shared, and archived.
It is a long, intricate, and sometimes repetitive work process.
But all of it is necessary for climbing the research ladder,
and getting to the last step to the results:
the data analysis.
But analyses will fail with data that lacks high quality.
The research may tumble. The errors that produce problems
are often born during the early stage of a project.
Research provides a large amount of valuable data, but,
even when the data are easy to retrieve,
small problems in its processing
can have a tremendous impact on the operability of the data.
Problems which are marginal issues at the start
steadily gain more importance.
The data are there, but they cannot be used or analyzed properly.
The data become worthless.
In the end, in order to save the project,
the data need to be decomposed or cleaned,
a process which is often difficult, sometimes dangerous,
and always time consuming.
By planning well ahead how the data will be analyzed,
one can best choose how the data should be collected
such that the data ends in its optimal position.
While surprises can always be expected,
the dangers are limited when an adequate file format is chosen.
But even more important than the data,
is its documentation, which must be cautiously designed and entered
or the data might become pointless.
Moving data from one format to another for its analysis is a considerable challenge.
Even computer readable data is tricky to migrate.
It is easy to underestimate the problem,
and it is tempting to think you will craft something later.
But "later" might become "too late".
There is a risk of total data loss.
Sometimes, with a lot of luck and efforts,
the data can be saved.
And sometimes not.
Because you do not want to evaluated or collected your data again:
Write a plan, document every step, produce tidy datasets.
Data management will make your data easy to analyze,
share, and re-use.
To learn more about data formats, structures, and documentation, look for help at a Research Data Management Helpdesk or online!
Translation: XXX
In the next episode, we will learn more about research data managers, stay tuned!