<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rdm on Promotion of Research data management, an open source Project.</title>
    <link>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/tags/rdm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rdm on Promotion of Research data management, an open source Project.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/tags/rdm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What we discovered so far</title>
      <link>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/08/20/what-we-discovered-so-far/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/08/20/what-we-discovered-so-far/</guid>
      <description>Method Here, we use the text collected and analysed so far (mostly via browsing the web, few direct contribution from the crowd), comparing it to a report from the research data alliance report. Both reports can be found as blog posts found under the category analysis.
Summary We focused our analysis on three interesting content: Marketing strategies (how to reach researchers), arguments for research data management, and stories to tell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysing the data</title>
      <link>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/07/05/analysing-the-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/07/05/analysing-the-data/</guid>
      <description>On this page, we will report the analysis of the data we gathered and collected, the page is recreated with updated data. The data itsel is created in a spreadsheet available on the github page. We welcome any of your comments in the blog comment section below.
For each argument, we gathered
 real life stories punch lines jokes, funny way to bring it reference to the (pop) culture wich could be used  list of arguments: Open data is inevitable</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>lost the backup</title>
      <link>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/06/27/lost-the-backup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/06/27/lost-the-backup/</guid>
      <description>The external hard drive is VERY important to me as it contains 5 years of research data which are crucial for my PhD thesis !!!
 I think comments are unnecessary.
Distributed under a CC-BY license, photo ©Peter Murray-Rust originally posted at https://blogs.ch.cam.ac.uk/pmr/2011/08/01/why-you-need-a-data-management-plan/
Collected by Julien Colomb, data manager</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exposing research data</title>
      <link>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/06/26/exposing-research-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/06/26/exposing-research-data/</guid>
      <description>In my work, I am the developer and administrator of a web based information system for research data applied in more than 30 research projects to share collected, brought or created data within the project consortium and with stakeholders. Even single researcher e.g. PhD students use the system to organize their own data. While most datasets can be downloaded without any extra request, few datasets can only be downloaded after the dataset owner approval.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>first draft of slideshow presentation for new professors v.0.1</title>
      <link>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/06/21/first-draft-of-slideshow-presentation-for-new-professors-v-0-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/06/21/first-draft-of-slideshow-presentation-for-new-professors-v-0-1/</guid>
      <description>This video is a first draft, I would be happy to get some feedback, about the storyline and the overall design. It is focused on the HU, because I will use it for my job interview there. A version aimed at the FSU will probably follow. This post may be updated when new versions of the video will be made.
You can download it here (the quality of the image is low on purpose): https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paper retraction in absence of data</title>
      <link>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/06/21/paper-retraction-in-absence-of-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/06/21/paper-retraction-in-absence-of-data/</guid>
      <description>see copyrighted material here: http://science.sciencemag.org/content/357/6352/654.1
In brief, a paper was retracted from science because the raw data could not be presented. The computer containing the data has apparently been stolen and no backup existed.
There are other similar stories on retractionwatch.com (https://retractionwatch.com/2016/02/23/we-are-living-in-hell-authors-retract-2nd-paper-due-to-missing-raw-data/, https://retractionwatch.com/2017/01/20/boom-headshot-disputed-video-game-paper-retracted/). It is not always clear if there were misconduct, but it seems the absence of data makes it impossible for researchers to prove they did not misconduct.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>open science and quality management 1</title>
      <link>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/06/01/open-science-and-quality-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/06/01/open-science-and-quality-management/</guid>
      <description>During the second week of march, I had the chance to participate to two interesting meetings: the open science barcamp and the premierquality seminar. Both events have some online archive with results of discussion for the barcamp (https://etherpad.wikimedia.org/p/oscibar2018) and slides of the presentations for the seminar (https://www.bihealth.org/de/quest-center/projekte/premier/news/). I was stroked by the similarity in the discourses, not only concerning the problems discussed but also the solutions proposed.
Here is the first of a series of blog about the parallel between the two events and communities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>my notes on possible new RDM promotion material</title>
      <link>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/05/31/my-notes-on-possible-new-rdm-promotion-material/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/05/31/my-notes-on-possible-new-rdm-promotion-material/</guid>
      <description>type of videos  hijack: computer game, superhero, star treck, star wars&amp;hellip; dialogue: research data VS GOfair research data data is my child chrismas present. hijack logical fallacies/known psychological events/dioseases,&amp;hellip;, give examples with data management  source of inspiration  phd comics https://theupturnedmicroscope.com, https://theupturnedmicroscope.com/comic/flash-comic-february-2016/, https://theupturnedmicroscope.com/comic/flash-comic-may-2015/, https://theupturnedmicroscope.com/comic/tip/, https://imgur.com/gallery/ZpgQz  topics  data loss
 you lost all your data but this todo list, it says: &amp;ldquo;backup data&amp;rdquo;  data documentation</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>my notes on possible new RDM promotion material</title>
      <link>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/post/my-notes-on-possible-new-rdm-promotion-material/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/post/my-notes-on-possible-new-rdm-promotion-material/</guid>
      <description>type of videos  hijack: computer game, superhero, star treck, star wars… dialogue: research data VS GOfair research data data is my child chrismas present. hijack logical fallacies/known psychological events/dioseases,…, give examples with data management   source of inspiration  phd comics https://theupturnedmicroscope.com, https://theupturnedmicroscope.com/comic/flash-comic-february-2016/, https://theupturnedmicroscope.com/comic/flash-comic-may-2015/, https://theupturnedmicroscope.com/comic/tip/, https://imgur.com/gallery/ZpgQz   topics  data loss  you lost all your data but this todo list, it says: “backup data”  data documentation  message to the future self if you read this, ….</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>