<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Promotion of Research data management, an open source Project.</title>
    <link>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Promotion of Research data management, an open source Project.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>link RDM with the open science movement via Wikimedia</title>
      <link>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/08/21/link-rdm-os-wikimedia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/08/21/link-rdm-os-wikimedia/</guid>
      <description>The very first Data Management Engagement Award, a competition sponsored by SPARC Europe, the University of Cambridge and Jisc to elicit new and imaginative ideas for engaging researchers in the practices of good Research Data Management (RDM).
Our proposal is to link RDM with the open science movement via the Wikimedia suite of tools.
Basically just share yours or others’ openly licensed research material via Wikimedia Commons to create an aggregated resource that can be used to improve Wikipedia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What we discovered so far</title>
      <link>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/08/20/what-we-discovered-so-far/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/08/20/what-we-discovered-so-far/</guid>
      <description>Method Here, we use the text collected and analysed so far (mostly via browsing the web, few direct contribution from the crowd), comparing it to a report from the research data alliance report. Both reports can be found as blog posts found under the category analysis.
Summary We focused our analysis on three interesting content: Marketing strategies (how to reach researchers), arguments for research data management, and stories to tell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>branding as data preparation for analysis</title>
      <link>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/08/20/branding-as-data-preparation-for-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/08/20/branding-as-data-preparation-for-analysis/</guid>
      <description>At the universisty of Jena, we have proposed lecture of data analysis. In the lecture, we presented research data management topics as a prerequisite for a good analysis.
This approach made it easier to &amp;ldquo;sell&amp;rdquo; it.
Distributed under a CC0 license
Collected by Julien Colomb, data manager</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>data archive is putting it out for discovery</title>
      <link>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/08/20/data-archive-is-putting-it-out-for-discovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/08/20/data-archive-is-putting-it-out-for-discovery/</guid>
      <description>The idea is to represent the idea that data archive is not putting the data in a place where nobody will ever look at it, but showing it to the world.
The idea is to represent a building, with a scienctist working at its computer and pushing the &amp;ldquo;archive the data&amp;rdquo; button. Then it would show someone in the basement shovelling data into the corners, which a voice over stating that it is what people think archiving is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>working strategies</title>
      <link>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/08/14/working-strategies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/08/14/working-strategies/</guid>
      <description>Modified from https://research-data-network.readme.io/docs/senior-management-engagement (reorganise text and add comments),
This is the result of the analyse of discussion in the UK community, remember that country specificities in working strategies and stories are to be expected.
Use senarios and story-telling Accusation of fraud We all agreed that one strategy that works for almost all possible audience types are doomsday scenarios – disasters that can happen when researchers do not adhere to good RDM practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Noon talks at the EPFL</title>
      <link>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/08/09/noon-talks-at-the-epfl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/08/09/noon-talks-at-the-epfl/</guid>
      <description>The Noon Talks are regular events that took place twice a year since 2016 at the Library. These events mainly cover scientific related topics such as preprints, open access, reusing content in theses, etc. The most efficient way to promote this event are our emailing list that we use to spread invitations on the campus. We obviously communicate as well on the common social media and via other channels (screens on the campus, online agendas, events lists, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mashup_data analysis</title>
      <link>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/08/07/mashup-data-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/08/07/mashup-data-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Topic: rdm for data analysis
template: Start with sth positive. one-liner problem. get the fixed content for all videos (time travel, rdm professional ,&amp;hellip;?)
explain what can be done to fix the problem.
Script: &amp;ldquo;It took a while for the scripts to run. I can still remember sitting there listening to the screeching sounds of the computer. And then one by one I got the results, and they all confirmed my hypothesis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>video mashups</title>
      <link>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/07/18/video-mashups/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/07/18/video-mashups/</guid>
      <description>The inspiration comes from ARTE: https://www.arte.tv/fr/videos/RC-015330/propaganda/ (french) https://www.arte.tv/de/videos/RC-015330/moneypulation/ (german), and I talk about the format, not the content :)
The idea is to create mashup videos, i.e. videos where the images are unrelated to the content but bring humor or a different perspective to what the voice off is saying. There is a lot of free to reuse videos available to do it.
The strategy to make some is to first write a script for the voice off and then look for the videos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>advertisment video</title>
      <link>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/07/06/advertisment-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/07/06/advertisment-video/</guid>
      <description>Links to interesting advertisment videos: giving ideas
http://www.culturepub.fr/videos/volkswagen-golf-kids-dreams/ we make future real (VW)
https://twitter.com/culturepub/status/1014081590706819072</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysing the data</title>
      <link>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/07/05/analysing-the-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/07/05/analysing-the-data/</guid>
      <description>On this page, we will report the analysis of the data we gathered and collected, the page is recreated with updated data. The data itsel is created in a spreadsheet available on the github page. We welcome any of your comments in the blog comment section below.
For each argument, we gathered
 real life stories punch lines jokes, funny way to bring it reference to the (pop) culture wich could be used  list of arguments: Open data is inevitable</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creative commons blog</title>
      <link>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/07/04/creative-commons/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/07/04/creative-commons/</guid>
      <description>Here are extracts from the blog.
Open Practices and Policies for Research Data in the Marine Community, from Alessandro Sarretta https://creativecommons.org/2016/12/01/open-practices-policies-research-data-marine-community/
As a researcher in the field(s) of Coastal and Marine Environment and Geospatial Information, I’m constantly dealing with data. Data are the core of science, and research has to be based on sound and reliable data.
My goal as an IOL fellow is to inform relevant marine communities of the benefits of an open research data policy and, more specifically, to apply these principles to the practices within my institute—the Institute of Marine Sciences (ISMAR), part of the Italian National Research Council.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open data is coming</title>
      <link>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/07/04/open-data-coming-proof/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/07/04/open-data-coming-proof/</guid>
      <description>Open data is coming, here are some data to backup this claim:
Carlos Moedas – Commissioner for Research, Science and Innovation - said on 22 June 2015:
 This will mean setting standards for the management, interoperability and quality of scientific data. I would like to see progress on this in next 12 months. And I will want to see what further support or requirements for open data should be introduced in Horizon 2020 following the mid term review.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>openscholarchampions</title>
      <link>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/07/04/openscholarchampions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/07/04/openscholarchampions/</guid>
      <description>Prof. Tuuli Toivonen on 5 June 2017, University of Helsinki https://openscholarchampions.eu/opendata/champion/changeresearchcultureforopendatadefault/
It was frustrating to know that valuable data had been collected but there was no access to that. The frustration was particularly intense if the data was collected by publicly-funded institutions that did not have the resources to really analyse the data. Then, we argued, that publicly-produced data should be mobilised for research. Or even better, we argued, it should be available for everyone without restrictions, to reduce the administrative workload and to reduce the barriers for collaboration and innovation between scientists, companies and active citizens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From the openadventures blog: 2</title>
      <link>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/07/03/from-the-openadventures-blog-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/07/03/from-the-openadventures-blog-2/</guid>
      <description>We report here abstract form the text present on the origina blog
Jennifer Harris and Tim Fulton (https://openadventures-blog.lib.cam.ac.uk/?p=90)
The task [asked by data manageers] is sometimes only a small one such as uploading a paper to an institutional repository post-publication. But these small tasks can sometimes be the final straw when it comes to managing your workload.
We have begun the process of preparing data for publication at the time of collection rather than as a subsequent publication step.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>youtube presentation note</title>
      <link>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/07/03/youtube-presentation-note/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/07/03/youtube-presentation-note/</guid>
      <description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hRoqQX97F6o&amp;amp;list=PLG24w6ETyHS3fYbDnB6LOOzOfATVhP3zp&amp;amp;index=16&amp;amp;t=0s
Tip of the day kind of communication very successful. Data steward as professional helpers in data management.
Avoid data disaster!
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bccJtgiM67c&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be
better to get a continuous flow of promotion coming that single workshops.
the added value of RDM and value of data.
Distributed under a CC0 license
Collected by Julien Colomb, data manager</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From the openadventures blog: 1 interviews</title>
      <link>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/07/02/from-the-openadventures-blog-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/07/02/from-the-openadventures-blog-1/</guid>
      <description>text obtained from: https://openadventures-blog.lib.cam.ac.uk
In a series of interview, data champions were asked to tell about their &amp;ldquo;happiest data moment.&amp;rdquo; Different answer were given.
David Marshall, @futurelib Around two years ago we (Futurelib) finished the data gathering phase of a project, Protolib, looking at the design of physical study spaces. We had prototyped different study spaces based on the findings of a collaborative design process conducted with Cambridge students and researchers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>lost the backup</title>
      <link>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/06/27/lost-the-backup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/06/27/lost-the-backup/</guid>
      <description>The external hard drive is VERY important to me as it contains 5 years of research data which are crucial for my PhD thesis !!!
 I think comments are unnecessary.
Distributed under a CC-BY license, photo ©Peter Murray-Rust originally posted at https://blogs.ch.cam.ac.uk/pmr/2011/08/01/why-you-need-a-data-management-plan/
Collected by Julien Colomb, data manager</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exposing research data</title>
      <link>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/06/26/exposing-research-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/06/26/exposing-research-data/</guid>
      <description>In my work, I am the developer and administrator of a web based information system for research data applied in more than 30 research projects to share collected, brought or created data within the project consortium and with stakeholders. Even single researcher e.g. PhD students use the system to organize their own data. While most datasets can be downloaded without any extra request, few datasets can only be downloaded after the dataset owner approval.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>first draft of slideshow presentation for new professors v.0.1</title>
      <link>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/06/21/first-draft-of-slideshow-presentation-for-new-professors-v-0-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/06/21/first-draft-of-slideshow-presentation-for-new-professors-v-0-1/</guid>
      <description>This video is a first draft, I would be happy to get some feedback, about the storyline and the overall design. It is focused on the HU, because I will use it for my job interview there. A version aimed at the FSU will probably follow. This post may be updated when new versions of the video will be made.
You can download it here (the quality of the image is low on purpose): https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>open FAIR data is coming</title>
      <link>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/06/21/open-fair-data-is-coming/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/06/21/open-fair-data-is-coming/</guid>
      <description>A scientist is sitting in the cafeteria, we ear people chatting:
 Do you know, you need to provide your data when you publish? The data should be in a state where it can be re-used. And each scientist is responsible for dealing with his data.  The scientist says: &amp;ldquo;That is bullshit: who is saying that?&amp;rdquo;
 Our main funders (DFG) Our favorite publishers Our employer, the university, is, too!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paper retraction in absence of data</title>
      <link>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/06/21/paper-retraction-in-absence-of-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/06/21/paper-retraction-in-absence-of-data/</guid>
      <description>see copyrighted material here: http://science.sciencemag.org/content/357/6352/654.1
In brief, a paper was retracted from science because the raw data could not be presented. The computer containing the data has apparently been stolen and no backup existed.
There are other similar stories on retractionwatch.com (https://retractionwatch.com/2016/02/23/we-are-living-in-hell-authors-retract-2nd-paper-due-to-missing-raw-data/, https://retractionwatch.com/2017/01/20/boom-headshot-disputed-video-game-paper-retracted/). It is not always clear if there were misconduct, but it seems the absence of data makes it impossible for researchers to prove they did not misconduct.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>data management fairy</title>
      <link>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/06/20/data-fairy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/06/20/data-fairy/</guid>
      <description>Narrator&amp;rsquo;s voice: Once upon a time, in the kingdom of academia, there worked a scientist. S/he worked night and day to collect the best, most reliable data in his/her field. Months of hard work went by. Until one day an evil spell was cast upon the kingdom. All the the research data with no backup should be lost forever!
&amp;ldquo;Why, oh why did I not backup my data?!&amp;rdquo; the researcher cried.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Idea: meta-analysis</title>
      <link>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/06/11/idea-meta-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/06/11/idea-meta-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Tim working at his computer. Two others speaking:
 What is Tim doing? Meta-analysis. whaa Cool, he is comparing his results with the data of other scientists got all over the world during the last 10 years? No that&amp;rsquo;s what the computer of Amanda, who is drinking coffee there is being doing&amp;hellip; Tim is just trying to compare his data, with the data he obtained two years ago. Slogan You want to manage your data like a pro, ask a pro  ##questions:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>fly olfactory learning and lab meta-analysis</title>
      <link>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/06/11/fly-olfactory-learning-and-lab-meta-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/06/11/fly-olfactory-learning-and-lab-meta-analysis/</guid>
      <description>In 2007, I entered a lab doing mainly one experiment: olfactory learning assay in fruit fly. The output of the experiment is the number of flies choosing one or the other odor, recorded manually on spreadsheets. For the 14 people in the lab, they were approximately 20 different spreadsheets around. We managed to create one tidy template for all experiments in about 6 months. Interestingly, it took 2-3 of us to design the first draft, we then gathered feedback from the whole group, get a second version and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>open science and quality management 1</title>
      <link>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/06/01/open-science-and-quality-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/06/01/open-science-and-quality-management/</guid>
      <description>During the second week of march, I had the chance to participate to two interesting meetings: the open science barcamp and the premierquality seminar. Both events have some online archive with results of discussion for the barcamp (https://etherpad.wikimedia.org/p/oscibar2018) and slides of the presentations for the seminar (https://www.bihealth.org/de/quest-center/projekte/premier/news/). I was stroked by the similarity in the discourses, not only concerning the problems discussed but also the solutions proposed.
Here is the first of a series of blog about the parallel between the two events and communities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>my notes on possible new RDM promotion material</title>
      <link>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/05/31/my-notes-on-possible-new-rdm-promotion-material/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/blog/2018/05/31/my-notes-on-possible-new-rdm-promotion-material/</guid>
      <description>type of videos  hijack: computer game, superhero, star treck, star wars&amp;hellip; dialogue: research data VS GOfair research data data is my child chrismas present. hijack logical fallacies/known psychological events/dioseases,&amp;hellip;, give examples with data management  source of inspiration  phd comics https://theupturnedmicroscope.com, https://theupturnedmicroscope.com/comic/flash-comic-february-2016/, https://theupturnedmicroscope.com/comic/flash-comic-may-2015/, https://theupturnedmicroscope.com/comic/tip/, https://imgur.com/gallery/ZpgQz  topics  data loss
 you lost all your data but this todo list, it says: &amp;ldquo;backup data&amp;rdquo;  data documentation</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>my notes on possible new RDM promotion material</title>
      <link>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/post/my-notes-on-possible-new-rdm-promotion-material/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/post/my-notes-on-possible-new-rdm-promotion-material/</guid>
      <description>type of videos  hijack: computer game, superhero, star treck, star wars… dialogue: research data VS GOfair research data data is my child chrismas present. hijack logical fallacies/known psychological events/dioseases,…, give examples with data management   source of inspiration  phd comics https://theupturnedmicroscope.com, https://theupturnedmicroscope.com/comic/flash-comic-february-2016/, https://theupturnedmicroscope.com/comic/flash-comic-may-2015/, https://theupturnedmicroscope.com/comic/tip/, https://imgur.com/gallery/ZpgQz   topics  data loss  you lost all your data but this todo list, it says: “backup data”  data documentation  message to the future self if you read this, ….</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/thanks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/thanks/</guid>
      <description>Partners This project was initiated inside the eeFDM (effective and efficient RDM) project, This project is conducted by the Research Data Management Helpdesk of the Friedrich-Schiller-Universität Jena, and was financed by the BMBF.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/contribute/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/contribute/</guid>
      <description>Make rdmpromotion your own project ! Thank you for considering a contribution to this project: we love your input! We want to make contributing to this project as easy, inclusive and transparent as possible (see also our code of conduct), whether it’s:
 Help with the website, outreach and give feedback. Add input (promotion material list, life-stories, idea for movies) Proposing new features, expanding the project Becoming a maintainer  All contribution will be under a permissive liscence (MIT for website, CC0 or CC-BY for contributions).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/empty/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/empty/</guid>
      <description>this is yet empty</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/promotion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/promotion/</guid>
      <description>    Image material on open license (including NC) Metadata for the image material Copyrighted material (links provided) videos listed via googlesheet   Image material on open license (including NC) (images are shown in small size, but high resolution, metadata indicated below)
 Metadata for the image material  {&#34;x&#34;:{&#34;url&#34;:&#34;/promotion_files/figure-html//widgets/widget_unnamed-chunk-2.html&#34;,&#34;options&#34;:{&#34;xdomain&#34;:&#34;*&#34;,&#34;allowfullscreen&#34;:false,&#34;lazyload&#34;:false}},&#34;evals&#34;:[],&#34;jsHooks&#34;:[]}  Copyrighted material (links provided) http://phdcomics.com/comics/archive_print.php?comicid=1531
http://phdcomics.com/comics/archive.php?comicid=382
 videos listed via googlesheet (https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1ybqL2WNdJZb7nwEAJ6yWJ0W95D3CtyEkQ97DFcJydsk/edit?usp=sharing)
 {&#34;x&#34;:{&#34;url&#34;:&#34;/promotion_files/figure-html//widgets/widget_unnamed-chunk-3.html&#34;,&#34;options&#34;:{&#34;xdomain&#34;:&#34;*&#34;,&#34;allowfullscreen&#34;:false,&#34;lazyload&#34;:false}},&#34;evals&#34;:[],&#34;jsHooks&#34;:[]}  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/teaching/</guid>
      <description>teaching RDM http://www.opensciencemooc.eu
http://rpubs.com/j_colomb/workshops</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/contact/</guid>
      <description>Email us The contact form is not working at the moment. Send an email to julien.colomb [at] fu-berlin.de to keep it touch</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FAQ</title>
      <link>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://be23bc55c79e487e7e627a4e31dbf59db88e6d3365926c987c319d185da63114/faq/</guid>
      <description> 1. Why is this site nearly empty The answer is simple:
 We are building a community to fill it up  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>