Research is a long process that relies on research data.
Data is collected, documented, processed,
preserved, shared, and archived,
It is a long, fastidious, sometimes repetitive work.
But all of it is necessary for climbing the research ladder,
getting to the final door before the results:
The data analysis.
But analysis fails with data lacking quality.
The research may tumble. The problems causing failure
are often born during the project youth.
Research is providing a large amount of valuable data, but,
even when the data is easy to retrieve,
small problems in its processing
can impact tremendously the operability of the data.
Problems which are marginal issues at the start
steadily assumes more importance
The data is there, but it cannot be used or analyzed.
The data become worthless.
In the end, in order to save the project,
the data needs to be decomposed or cleaned,
a process which is difficult, sometimes dangerous,
and always time consuming.
By planning well ahead how the data will be analyzed,
one can best choose how the data should be collected
such that the data ends in its most well fitted position.
While surprises are always expected,
the dangers are limited when
an adequate file format is chosen.
But even more important than the data,
its documentation must be designed and filled cautiously
or the data might become pointless.
Moving data from one format to another for its analysis
is a considerable challenge. Even computer readable data
is tricky to migrate.
It is easy to underestimate the problem,
it is tempting to think one will craft something later.
But "later" might become "too late".
Sometimes the data must be re-evaluated completely.
Sometimes, with a lot of luck and efforts,
the data can be saved.
But counting on luck is not very sound, is it?
Instead, start early with your research data management:
Write a plan, document every step, produce tidy datasets:
Be clever and your data will be easy to analyze
and share.
Learn more about data formats, structures, and documentation,
seek for help at a Research Data Management Helpdesk or online !
In our next episode, we will learn more about research data managers, stay tuned !