Research is a long process that relies on research data.
Data is created or collected, processed,
documented,  analyzed, preserved, stored,
shared, used, re-analyzed and re-used.
It is a fastidious, sometimes repetitive work.
But all of it is necessary for climbing the research ladder.
Up the stairs, one door leads to the research results,
data analysis can open that door,
but only if the research data CAN be analyzed.
The research may tumble. The problems causing failure
are often born during the project youth,
and they are difficult to fix a posteriori.
Research is providing a large amount of valuable data, but,
even when the data is easy to retrieve,
small problems in its processing
can impact tremendously the operability of the data.
Problem which are marginal issues at the start
steadily assumes more importance
to become huge problems years later:
The data is there, but it cannot be used or analyzed.
The data become worthless.
In the end, in order to save the project,
the data needs to be decomposed or cleaned,
a process which is difficult, sometimes dangerous,
and always time consuming.
To plan the use and re-use of the data,
its format must be adapted.
In particular, computer readable digital datasets do
open windows of opportunities, when the unexpected happens.
By planning well ahead how the data will be analyzed,
one can best choose how the data should be collected
such that the data ends in its most well fitted position.
While surprises are always expected,
the dangers are limited when
an adequate file format is chosen.
But even more important than the data,
its documentation must be designed and filled cautiously
or the data might become pointless.
Research Data Management not only
makes it more convenient to analyze the data,
but, by introducing standards, it allows the data
to find its place in the research community.
Moving data from one format to another is a considerable challenge.
Even interoperable and machine readable data
is tricky to migrate.
It does not come without danger either.
It is easy to underestimate the problem,
it is tempting to think one will craft something later.
But "later" might become "too late".
Sometimes the data must be re-evaluated completely.
Sometimes, with a lot of luck and efforts,
the data can be saved.
But counting on luck is not very sound, is it?
Instead, start early with your research data management
Make a data management plan, it is a witty move!
Get training, master the data life cycle,
make your spreadsheets tidy, document your data flow.
Be a researcher and a research data manager.
And in five years, your data will be easy to analyze
and share.
Learn more about data formats, structures, and documentation,
seek for help at a Research Data management helpdesk or online !
In our next episode, we will learn more about research data managers, stay tuned !