The researchers do love their data
And if the data is lost, the dance stops
While researchers can avoid
the crash of a complete data loss by doing backups.
proper data management goes
beyond just preventing a crash
Data is accumulating fast
While packing their data for
future analysis, reuse, and sharing,
the researchers often lack a system.
This strategy may work on the short term
but when the amound and complexity of datasets increase,
the researchers put themselves in danger !
Because you do not want to spend days sorting out your data,
you shall master data safety, organization, naming and computer readability.
Then, the process happens smoothly and efficiently.
You want to master data management and increase your efficiency, seek for help at a research data management helpdesk or online.
In the next episode, we will see how research data management can help you to produce easier and powerful data analysis, so stay tuned !