<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Collected Data on Promotion of Research data management, an open source Project.</title>
    <link>dat://22185fbab02c357e9ded9a2138bf0b7797acb04453cd6f69ea5f5741d96c5ae5/tags/collected-data/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Collected Data on Promotion of Research data management, an open source Project.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="dat://22185fbab02c357e9ded9a2138bf0b7797acb04453cd6f69ea5f5741d96c5ae5/tags/collected-data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Noon talks at the EPFL</title>
      <link>dat://22185fbab02c357e9ded9a2138bf0b7797acb04453cd6f69ea5f5741d96c5ae5/blog/2018/08/09/noon-talks-at-the-epfl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://22185fbab02c357e9ded9a2138bf0b7797acb04453cd6f69ea5f5741d96c5ae5/blog/2018/08/09/noon-talks-at-the-epfl/</guid>
      <description>The Noon Talks are regular events that took place twice a year since 2016 at the Library. These events mainly cover scientific related topics such as preprints, open access, reusing content in theses, etc. The most efficient way to promote this event are our emailing list that we use to spread invitations on the campus. We obviously communicate as well on the common social media and via other channels (screens on the campus, online agendas, events lists, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creative commons blog</title>
      <link>dat://22185fbab02c357e9ded9a2138bf0b7797acb04453cd6f69ea5f5741d96c5ae5/blog/2018/07/04/creative-commons/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://22185fbab02c357e9ded9a2138bf0b7797acb04453cd6f69ea5f5741d96c5ae5/blog/2018/07/04/creative-commons/</guid>
      <description>Here are extracts from the blog.
Open Practices and Policies for Research Data in the Marine Community, from Alessandro Sarretta https://creativecommons.org/2016/12/01/open-practices-policies-research-data-marine-community/
As a researcher in the field(s) of Coastal and Marine Environment and Geospatial Information, I’m constantly dealing with data. Data are the core of science, and research has to be based on sound and reliable data.
My goal as an IOL fellow is to inform relevant marine communities of the benefits of an open research data policy and, more specifically, to apply these principles to the practices within my institute—the Institute of Marine Sciences (ISMAR), part of the Italian National Research Council.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open data is coming</title>
      <link>dat://22185fbab02c357e9ded9a2138bf0b7797acb04453cd6f69ea5f5741d96c5ae5/blog/2018/07/04/open-data-coming-proof/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://22185fbab02c357e9ded9a2138bf0b7797acb04453cd6f69ea5f5741d96c5ae5/blog/2018/07/04/open-data-coming-proof/</guid>
      <description>Open data is coming, here are some data to backup this claim:
Carlos Moedas – Commissioner for Research, Science and Innovation - said on 22 June 2015:
 This will mean setting standards for the management, interoperability and quality of scientific data. I would like to see progress on this in next 12 months. And I will want to see what further support or requirements for open data should be introduced in Horizon 2020 following the mid term review.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>openscholarchampions</title>
      <link>dat://22185fbab02c357e9ded9a2138bf0b7797acb04453cd6f69ea5f5741d96c5ae5/blog/2018/07/04/openscholarchampions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://22185fbab02c357e9ded9a2138bf0b7797acb04453cd6f69ea5f5741d96c5ae5/blog/2018/07/04/openscholarchampions/</guid>
      <description>Prof. Tuuli Toivonen on 5 June 2017, University of Helsinki https://openscholarchampions.eu/opendata/champion/changeresearchcultureforopendatadefault/
It was frustrating to know that valuable data had been collected but there was no access to that. The frustration was particularly intense if the data was collected by publicly-funded institutions that did not have the resources to really analyse the data. Then, we argued, that publicly-produced data should be mobilised for research. Or even better, we argued, it should be available for everyone without restrictions, to reduce the administrative workload and to reduce the barriers for collaboration and innovation between scientists, companies and active citizens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From the openadventures blog: 2</title>
      <link>dat://22185fbab02c357e9ded9a2138bf0b7797acb04453cd6f69ea5f5741d96c5ae5/blog/2018/07/03/from-the-openadventures-blog-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://22185fbab02c357e9ded9a2138bf0b7797acb04453cd6f69ea5f5741d96c5ae5/blog/2018/07/03/from-the-openadventures-blog-2/</guid>
      <description>We report here abstract form the text present on the origina blog
Jennifer Harris and Tim Fulton (https://openadventures-blog.lib.cam.ac.uk/?p=90)
The task [asked by data manageers] is sometimes only a small one such as uploading a paper to an institutional repository post-publication. But these small tasks can sometimes be the final straw when it comes to managing your workload.
We have begun the process of preparing data for publication at the time of collection rather than as a subsequent publication step.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From the openadventures blog: 1 interviews</title>
      <link>dat://22185fbab02c357e9ded9a2138bf0b7797acb04453cd6f69ea5f5741d96c5ae5/blog/2018/07/02/from-the-openadventures-blog-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://22185fbab02c357e9ded9a2138bf0b7797acb04453cd6f69ea5f5741d96c5ae5/blog/2018/07/02/from-the-openadventures-blog-1/</guid>
      <description>text obtained from: https://openadventures-blog.lib.cam.ac.uk
In a series of interview, data champions were asked to tell about their &amp;ldquo;happiest data moment.&amp;rdquo; Different answer were given.
David Marshall, @futurelib Around two years ago we (Futurelib) finished the data gathering phase of a project, Protolib, looking at the design of physical study spaces. We had prototyped different study spaces based on the findings of a collaborative design process conducted with Cambridge students and researchers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>lost the backup</title>
      <link>dat://22185fbab02c357e9ded9a2138bf0b7797acb04453cd6f69ea5f5741d96c5ae5/blog/2018/06/27/lost-the-backup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://22185fbab02c357e9ded9a2138bf0b7797acb04453cd6f69ea5f5741d96c5ae5/blog/2018/06/27/lost-the-backup/</guid>
      <description>The external hard drive is VERY important to me as it contains 5 years of research data which are crucial for my PhD thesis !!!
 I think comments are unnecessary.
Distributed under a CC-BY license, photo ©Peter Murray-Rust originally posted at https://blogs.ch.cam.ac.uk/pmr/2011/08/01/why-you-need-a-data-management-plan/
Collected by Julien Colomb, data manager</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paper retraction in absence of data</title>
      <link>dat://22185fbab02c357e9ded9a2138bf0b7797acb04453cd6f69ea5f5741d96c5ae5/blog/2018/06/21/paper-retraction-in-absence-of-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>dat://22185fbab02c357e9ded9a2138bf0b7797acb04453cd6f69ea5f5741d96c5ae5/blog/2018/06/21/paper-retraction-in-absence-of-data/</guid>
      <description>see copyrighted material here: http://science.sciencemag.org/content/357/6352/654.1
In brief, a paper was retracted from science because the raw data could not be presented. The computer containing the data has apparently been stolen and no backup existed.
There are other similar stories on retractionwatch.com (https://retractionwatch.com/2016/02/23/we-are-living-in-hell-authors-retract-2nd-paper-due-to-missing-raw-data/, https://retractionwatch.com/2017/01/20/boom-headshot-disputed-video-game-paper-retracted/). It is not always clear if there were misconduct, but it seems the absence of data makes it impossible for researchers to prove they did not misconduct.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>